# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hello everyone, this is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
In this video, I would like to share with you a homestyle dish
# 牛蛙鱼头
Niu Wa Yu Tou (Bullfrog with fish head)
# 首先我们准备牛蛙4只
Firstly, prepare 4 bullfrogs
# 去掉外皮和内脏清洗干净备用
Remove the skin and internal organs and wash them thoroughly
# 考虑宰杀这一步比较血腥
Since the butchering step is relatively bloody
# 所以嫌麻烦的同学可以交给摊主处理
Please leave it to the shopkeeper if you don't want to do it
# 中途用剪刀去掉牛蛙的脚趾
Remove the fingers of the frogs with scissors
# 然后再从中间剪开备用
Then cut it open in the middle for further use
# 牛蛙处理好之后 下一步开始处理鱼头
When the frog is done, deal with the fish head
# 准备鲜活的花鲢一条
Prepare a healthy, living silver carp
# 将鱼敲晕之后去除鱼鳞和内脏
Stun it and remove the scales and internal organs
# 然后将鱼头取下清洗干净备用
Separate the fish head from the body and wash it thoroughly for further use
# 处理的时候可以从鱼头背部下刀切开
Cut the head open from the backside of the fish
# 这样更容易取鳃和清洗
Such that you can remove the gill and wash it easily
# 主料备齐之后下一步开始准备辅料
When all the major ingredients are ready, start preparing the Fuliao (side ingredients)
# 准备酸菜一小把清洗干净之后切成小块备用
Prepare some fermented vegetables and cut it into small pieces
# 加酸菜的目的是增鲜提味
The purpose of this step is to enhance the savory flavor in the dish
# 准备生姜1块拍散之后剁碎备用
Squash a piece of ginger and chop it into small pieces
# 准备大蒜40克切成小粒备用
Cut 40 grams of garlic into small pieces
# 准备适量的红泡椒切成小粒备用
Cut a moderate amount of red fermented chili into small pieces
# 准备麻辣火锅底料50克切散备用
Smash 50 grams of spicy hot-pot ingredient
# 底料不受任何品牌限制
You can use the ingredient of any brand
# 准备干辣椒一小把剪成小节备用
Cut a handful of dried red chili into small pieces with scissors
# 碗中再加入适量的青花椒备用
Add some Sichuan peppercorn into the bowl
# 下一步开始准备打底菜
Then, prepare the "Da di cai" (vegetables at the bottom of the bowl) #请检查这里的表达
# 准备豆芽1小把备用
Prepare a handful of bean sprouts
# 准备芹菜几根切成小段放入盆中垫底
Cut some celery into pieces and put it in the bowl
# 同学们也可以根据个人喜好添加底菜
You can use your favorite vegetables as the base vegetable #请检查这里的表达
# 下一步开始制作
Next, cook the dish
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First, heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入少许的底油
Add some "Di you" (base oil) into the wok
# 油热之后加入适量的干辣椒爆锅
When the oil is hot, put some dried chili into the wok
# 辣椒变色之后加入准备好的豆芽爆炒几下炒至断生
As the color of the chili changes, put the bean sprouts into the wok and cook them till "Duan sheng" (80% done)
# 中途加入少许的食用盐调底味
Add some salt for the basic flavor
# 炒至断生之后倒入盆中垫底备用
When the bean sprouts are "Duan sheng", transfer them into the bowl
# 然后我们再次把锅烧热
Then, heat up the wok again
# 锅烧热之后加入熟菜籽油50克烧至6成热
Add 50 grams of "Shu cai zi you" (rapeseed oil that has been heated) and heat it until 60% hot
# 油温6成热之后加入准备好的料头下锅爆香
Add the prepared "liao tou" (seasoning ingredients, such as garlic, ginger, etc) and cook them until aromatic #请检查这里的表达
# 中途再加入切好的火锅底料和酸菜
Add the chopped hot-pot ingredient and fermented vegetable into the wok halfway
# 然后转小火翻炒3分钟将底料炒香炒化
Cook with low heat for 3 minutes to melt the hot-pot ingredient
# 底料炒香之后加入适量的清水开大火烧开
Then add a moderate amount of water and boil with high heat
# 大火烧开之后开始调味
After boiled, season the soup
# 锅中加入食用盐1大勺（约5克）
Add a big spoon of salt (~ 5 grams)
# 加入胡椒粉1勺（约1克）
A spoon of pepper powder (~ 1 gram)
# 加入五香粉1勺（约0.5克）
A spoon of "Wu xiang fen" (~ 0.5 gram)
# 加入鸡精2勺（约4克）
Two spoons of essence of chicken (~ 4 grams)
# 加入白糖少许中和辣味
And some sugar to neutralize the spicy flavor
# 最后再加入生抽酱油8克
Finally, add 8 grams of light soy sauce
# 调好味之后将准备好的鱼头和牛蛙下锅
After seasoning, put the frog and the fish head into the wok
# 因为牛蛙和鱼头是现杀所以不需要提前腌制
You don't need to marinade them in advance because they are fresh
# 主料下锅之后转中小火烧8分钟
Boil them with low heat for 8 minutes
# 这一步的目的是将其煮熟煮至入味
The purpose of this step is to cook them and let the flavor go inside
# 8分钟之后将主料捞出放入盆中
8 minutes later, take out the major ingredients and put them into the bowl
# 然后再加入适量的原汤
Then add some original soup
# 下一步开始准备泼油
Next, pour hot oil onto the dish
# 首先我们再次把锅烧热
Heat up the wok again
# 锅烧热之后加入熟菜籽油500克
Add 500 grams of "Shu cai zi you" when the wok is hot
# 将油温烧至4成热之后加入准备好的辣椒和花椒
Heat the oil till 40% hot and add dried chili and Sichuan peppercorns
# 然后转大火不停的搅动辣椒
Then turn to high heat and stir the chili
# 将辣椒烧至棕色之后再一次性泼在牛蛙和鱼头上面
When the chili turns brown, pour the oil onto the frog and fish head at a time
# 最后再撒上适量的香菜即可
Finally, sprinkle some coriander on the surface
# 一道重口美味的牛蛙鱼头就制作完成
A heavy-flavor, delicious Bullfrog with Fish Head is ready to serve!
# 下面开始技术总结
This is the summary
# 第一，牛蛙和鱼头必须选择现场宰杀，否则不鲜有腥味
First, the bullfrogs and fish must be butchered right before cooking, or they might taste bad and smell unpleasant
# 第二，牛蛙和鱼头都不用提前腌制
Second, you don't need to marinade the bullfrog and the fish before cooking
# 第三，此菜在后期煮制的时候必须小火慢煮这样才能入味
Third, make sure to use low heat to boil the meat so that the flavor can go into them
# 第四，嫌麻烦的同学可以交给摊主宰杀
Fourth, you can ask the shopkeeper to butcher the frog or the fish
# 牛蛙鱼头的技术总结完毕
That's the end of the summary